
<Root>
	NOTE: I've currently filled this with my own style as a template. This means that it is subject to change as we see fit.
	
	<Style_Guide>
		<Description>
			-The xml format is used. This is so that parts can be easily organized into sections. As well as this, xml viewers will
			 allow the ability to collapse sections so that the viewer can collapse the ones that they do not want to see.
			-Description section
				-Points for descriptions are indicated with a "-". This is so that the viewer can easily distinguish separate points
				 when points are multi line.
				-When points are multiline, the next line is indented with a single space to indicate that it is part of the previous
				 line. This also alignes the start of the next line with the start of the previous line of text (accounts for the "-"). 
		</Description>
	</Style_Guide>
	
	<Github>
		-Each device that access the github must uses it's own working branch when modifying code Eample "ConnerDesktopWorking"
		-The branch must be reviewed before it is merged into the main branch.
	</Github>
		
	<CPP>
		<Curly_Braces>
			<Description>
				-Open and close on their own, separate lines
				-Control blocks must include curly brackets
				-If the items inside of a control block only contain a couple statements, the entire thing can be written on a single
				 line. Discression must be used when determining when to use this. The purpose of this is to group slightly longer bits
				 of code into a compact block for ease of reading. This is also used for when the calculation is used only once or 
				 twice and doesn't deserve it's own special function.
				-It is acceptable to use curly braces to control scope and section off code into sub sections within a function.
			</Description>
			
			<Good_Example>
				if (condition)
				{
					foo()
				}
				
				if (i) { foo(); }
				
				//defines a scope
				{
					int localvar;
				}
				//local var no longer exists
			</Good_Example>
			
			<Bad_Example>
				if (condition) {
					foo();
				}
			
				if (condition)
					foo();
				
				if (condition) { if (condition2) { stuff(); stuff2(); if (condition2) { stuff3(); } } }
			</Bad_Example>
		</Curly_Braces>
			
		<Pointers>
			<Description>
				-the '*' is always located attatched to the variable. This is to both save space and avoid the last bad example.
			</Description>
			
			<Good_Example>
				int *a = 0;
				*a = new int(3);
				*a = *a + 3
				int *b, *c, *d;
			</Good_Example>
			
			<Bad_Example>
				int * a;
				int* b;
				int* c, * d, * e;
			</Bad_Example>
		</Pointers>
				
		<Naming_Convention>
			-Local Variables
				-Camel case
				 This is to signify that the variable is only local
			-Global Variables
				-Capitalize each word
				 This is to distinguish between local variables and global variables
			-Class Member Variables
				-Capitalized
				 This is to signify that this is a member variable that has scope of the entire class. This is also useful when a local
				 variable would likely have a same name but there needs to be a way to distinguish them. For example, for setter
				 functions having the same name as the member variables that they are setting.
			-Function Names	
				-Capitalize each word
				 This is to further differentiate functions as being separate from variables
			-Macros
				-All Caps with Underscores seperating words
		</Naming_Convention>
		
		<File_Layout>
			<Description>
				-Header Guard uses #ifndef-#define-#endif blocks for the header guard
				-Header files do not contain actual executed code; that must be placed in a cpp file instead.
			</Description>
		</File_Layout>
	</CPP>
	
	<Java>
		NOTE:: Use the C++ style guide as a template but it may differ due to differing language styles
		NOTE:: I (Conner) will not make any definitive decisions for the Java style guide since i will not be dealing with this part
		 of the code as much. It is up to those who will be writing most of this code to determine the style guide.
	</Java>
			 
</Root>
